PAUL V. SORIANO

723 Schooner Lane, Elk Grove Village, IL 60007 · (312) 371-2264 pvsoriano@me.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulvsoriano/ · https://paulvsoriano.com

Security architect with 14+ years of experience and a deep passion for security. Proven experience in understanding business objectives, determining security requirements and developing effective security solutions. Reputation for effectively operating at strategic, operational and tactical levels.

EXPERIENCE

FEBRUARY 2019 - PRESENT

MANAGER, IDENTITY & ARCHITECTURE, DELTA DENTAL PLANS ASSOCIATION

Responsible for the development of infrastructure and security architecture designs and standards, driving the strategy and execution of the IAM program, and cloud strategy & design.

JANUARY 2017 – JANUARY 2019

MANAGER, SECURITY ARCHITECTURE, DELTA DENTAL PLANS ASSOCIATION

Responsible for defining security requirements for all company projects, developing security architecture designs and designing/implementing all technical security projects.

MAY 2016 - DECEMBER 2016

IT SECURITY ARCHITECTURE MANAGER, ZURICH INSURANCE COMPANY

Led a team of 3 in developing security requirements and architectural designs for enterprise projects, including cost estimations and delivery approaches. Responsible for developing global IT security standards, reference architectures and global security strategies.

DECEMBER 2014 – APRIL 2016

IT SECURITY ARCHITECT, ZURICH INSURANCE COMPANY

Lead security architect responsible for the security architecture and design of the new EMEA data centers. Evaluated and recommended security products and solutions aligning to business and IT requirements.

NOVEMBER 2013 - NOVEMBER 2014

IT SECURITY ARCHITECT, CNO FINANCIAL GROUP / BANKERS LIFE

Developed security requirements and architectural designs for enterprise projects, performed security assessments of internal and 3rd party systems, and conducted all enterprise 3rd party security risk assessments.

JANUARY 2012 – OCTOBER 2013

BUSINESS SOLUTIONS & SUPPORT MANAGER, CNO FINANCIAL GROUP /

BANKERS LIFE

Led company mobility initiatives while managing a team of 7 to provide business application support. Managed and lead the development and implementation of our prospecting mobile application resulting in over \$2 million in new annualized premium.

AUGUST 2008 – DECEMBER 2011

SERVICE DESK MANAGER, CNO FINANCIAL GROUP / BANKERS LIFE

Responsible for a team of 6, providing enterprise Level 1 support for 10,000+ users, fielding over 140,000 calls annually.

JANUARY 2006 – JULY 2008

FIELD SERVICES SUPERVISOR, CNO FINANCIAL GROUP / BANKERS LIFE

JANUARY 2003 - DECEMBER 2005

NETWORK & SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR, UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT CHICAGO

AUGUST 1998 – AUGUST 2002

SERGEANT / TEAM LEADER, UNITED STATES ARMY

EDUCATION

MAY 2006

B.S., MATHEMATICS & COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT CHICAGO

Minor: Psychology

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Security Specialty AWS-SCS (2019)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate AWS-SAA (2018)
- (ISC)2: Certified Cloud Security Professional CCSP (2017)
- EC-Council: Certified Ethical Hacker C|EH (2017)
- ISACA: Certified Information Security Manager CISM (2016)
- ISACA: Certified Information Systems Auditor CISA (2015)
- (ISC)2: Information Systems Security Architecture Professional CISSP-ISSAP (2014)
- (ISC)2: Certified Information Systems Security Professional CISSP (2013)
- ITIL Foundations v3 (2008)
- CompTIA: Security+ (2005)
- CompTIA: Network+ (2005)
- CompTIA: A+ (2002)